Peter Sheng-Wen Lai

22 Olive Ave, Toronto, Ontario, M2N 7G6

peterlai60917@outlook.com (416)825-6051 https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-lai-mba-6467879a/

PROFILE STATEMENT

Experienced technology sales professional with a focus on AI, Machine Learning, Nvidia GPU, cloud, data infrastructure, SaaS, IT technology and cyber risk within financial institutions and multiple vertical markets. My career within technology and cyber risk is underpinned by my over 10 years of global experience in the technology sector, understanding a broad range of IoT/SaaS platforms and technologies; Quota-carrying sales leader, I quarterback sales via BANT and MEDDIC within the region through consultative selling techniques to develop leads (cold calls, cold mails, LinkedIn Sales Navigator, Zoominfo) and create solutions for Smart Manufacturing, Vision Inspections, Remote Connectivity/Monitoring and Data Analytics solutions.

EDUCATION

Schulich School of Business, York University

Masters of Business Administration

• Academic Specialization: Financial Stream

• Academic: Leader of MBA capstone project

National Chengchi University

Bachelors of Arts: Arabic Language

Taipei, Taiwan Jun, 2013

Toronto, Canada

Jan, 2023

- Academic: Deep dive middle eastern culture and stayed in Tunisia in 2011 to master the language
- Volunteer: Experience in helping immigrant workers in Taiwan adapt to the society by providing regular coaching and mentorship

EXPERIENCE

Lanner Electronics Inc. Canada

Toronto, Canada

Account Manager

Oct 2023 -

- Facilitate strong and productive partnership with ecosystem partners and key accounts at the highest levels of customer service standards
- Uncover growth opportunities with existing and new customers; successful penetration into 10 PoC opportunities at start of three months
- Propose creative technical solutions to win opportunities within embedded computing and AI edge gateways and negotiate win-win agreements to close deals
- Recruit alliance partners to join Lanner's solutions to transform sales pattern from products to solutions; on-board 3 partners to join at start of three months

Avnan Electro Inc. Toronto, Canada Account Executive Jul 2023- Oct. 2023

 Develop a portfolio of accounts within IT/Manufacturing industries along with a focus on driving revenue growth and maximizing profitability; Successfully built a strong pipeline of \$250K business in first 2 months

- **Uncover** growth opportunities with existing and new customers look for ways to create customer value; Upsell existing clients for incremental revenue for the organization
- Propose creative technical solutions to win opportunities and negotiate win-win agreements to close deals
- Relationship management including key accounts, book of business, growth, retention
- Plan thorough client follow-up playbook to ensure the leads are warmed; Reached over 3.4K contacts in first

Deloitte LLP Toronto, Canada Feb 2023- May 2023 Consultant, Cyber Risk Services

Compliance: Helped clients assess existing environment and provide thorough intelligence to indicate the gap to fully comply with SOC2/ISO27001/NIST; Worked with leading fintech company in Canada to perform cyber due diligence

- Assessment: Referred to security risk assessments including HIPAA and PCI-DSS to help organizations keep compliant with a unified set of security controls that are implemented and agreed upon by such governing bodies
- Analysis: Used Enterprise Risk Management tools, practices, and policies to analyze and report enterprise risks, and to manage risks according to an enterprise risk management framework. Ensured the organization's risk management policies and strategies are in compliance with applicable regulations, rating agency standards
- Set Best Practices: Partnered with stakeholders from ORM, Risk and Control and various Back Office departments to establish SOX and ORM best practices
- Data: Assisted clients in developing a better understanding of the personal, sensitive, and confidential information they collect, process, and share
- Identity: Leveraged Deloitte's Identity methodologies and Digital Identity platform to help clients control which employees, partners, suppliers, customers, and citizens access sensitive organizational applications and data
- Strategy, Defense, and Response: Helped clients design and implement transformational enterprise security programs with an emphasis on defending against, recovering from, and remediating major cyberattacks; Helped with several proposal to win the deals for one of the biggest food supplier and public pension companies in
- Governance and Regulation: Kept abreast of various external cyber trends and regulatory changes to reduce cyber risk exposure and manage cyber risk
- **Communication:** Worked with various functional personnel to ensure that clients' internal controls are adequately designed and monitored; Developed and maintained internal control documentation within clients' organizations and related processes to ensure compliance with control framework; Coordinated with internal & external audit, and assist in the timely closure of any identified improvement opportunities

Pleora Technologies Toronto, Canada May 2022- Dec 2022 (Contract)

Sales Development Representative

- Business Development: Prioritized and qualified prospective 20-30 leads on daily basis through outbound mails and calls, while ensuring that lead, contact and opportunity records are complete and accurate
- Team Coordination: Worked with Sales and Marketing teams to identify ongoing strategic targets to nurture pipelines; grew \$100K pipeline to \$350K during 8-month tenure
- Sales Funnel: Built complete sales funnel through nurturing to closing deal via curated marketing information, detailed product spec-in and pricing negotiation
- Brand Awareness: Promoted the brand to all possibly potential users including camera OEM, factory automation system integrators and academic research organizations to educate the necessity of faster interface of camera and no-code/low-code AI machine vision software
- Quota Carrying: Met and exceeded the assigned quota by using cold mails, cold calls, Linkedin Sales Navigator and Zoominfo to touch base with potential users and understand their scenario to propose the suitable solution

Advantech Co. Ltd. Taiwan/India Apr 2017-Aug 2021

Sector Head, South Asia, Embedded IoT Group

- Team Leader: Oversaw 3 major pillars of business within Advantech ranging from Key Account to Channel with a team of 7
- Quota Carrying: Achieved over 3.5 million business size in 2017, 5.3 million business size with over 50% YoY rate and foreseeable growth in 2018
- New Business: Took charge of new business development to ensure 5 key accounts and 40-50 potential leads are added to business pipelines; Led Advanech into SD-WAN market by initiating with leading telecommunication/ICT companies in India and brought in over \$2M business revenue
- Cloud Development: Pivoted the existing business to new emerging market: SaaS and Cloud by introducing

- SaaS-based smart manufacturing solutions and signing the agreement with Microsoft to distribute Azure services to add incremental revenue to the business
- **Eco-System Builder**: Acted as important liaison to work closely with important industry leader like AMD, Intel and Nvidia to ensure Advantech is at the edge of market offering; Created different unique solutions to expedite adoption of IoT knowledge; Worked with one world-renowned glass/bottle OEM to implement IoT solutions by bringing in partners like Microsoft and local system integrator to ensure the requirement is met
- Marketing: Worked closely with marketing team to design and come up with different marketing activities on quarterly basis to ensure taylor-made marketing activities can arouse users' demand from different segments i.e. leveraged email canvassing to reach potential users to assist in online business and invited partners/distributors to have IT roadshows across India to ensure we cover different regions' important industry leaders

Shuttle Inc.Taipei, TaiwanAccount ExecutiveMay 2015-Apr 2017

- Incremental Performance: Managed to grow sales turn-up in S.E. Asia market with 40% YoY
- New Market Development: Turned Vietnam from a country with zero sales to over 2000 pieces contribution by working with leading education solution provider in Vietnam to propose Smart White Board solutions to the authorities concerned; Set the first flag in Laos by working with the biggest ICT distributor in Laos to create brand awareness and first sales in the country
- **New Distributorship**: Independently grew sales in Singapore market with establishing 2nd distributorship and the venture brought the brand into emerging tech trend including gaming, automatic number-plate recognition/traffic solutions, hospitality and F&B industry